# Nitay Yacobovitch

054-6692505



https://nitayya.github.io/Nitay/



https://www.linkedin.com/in/nitayya/



nitayya@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

Expanding my skills by participating in a "Data Engineer" Certification course in Naya College 2 years experience as a BI Analyst for a product software company delivering ML and AI solution for US retailers and FCMG. Working with very large data sets using big data technologies (SQL, Python, Visualization Tools, ETL and more...)

Information Systems Management (Ben-Gurion University) Graduate

# **SKILLS**

#### Development skills -

- Python Developed 'System output validator' tool that reduces the manual work of my team on it. The tool was
  developed using various libraries such as Pandas, NumPy, logging, sqlalchemy
- Java, OOP
- JS, PHP, HTML, CSS

# Data Technologies-

- SQL proficiency
- Hadoop Framework, Kafka, NoSQL DBs, AWS infrastructure
- Cloud infrastructure (mainly AWS)
- DWH (including data modeling, ETL/ELT processes
- Visualization/BI tools: Tableau, Power-BI, Talend

# **CAREER**

# **2020 - PRESENT**

#### **BI ANALYST**

## Sagarmatha

- Working with a US based retailer, to target personalized coupons within their loyalty program, including:
  - Querying from various large & complex data sets (SQL Server, Exasol), executing ad-hoc anylysis to detect patterns based on shopper's behavior to improve business decision making
  - Setup, calibrate, execute and monitor the personalization ML engine (Sagarmatha's propriety software)
  - Worked closely within a team of Data analysts and BI developers to define ETL processes and analytic reports
  - Responsibility for all on-going operation activities, while working with oversea customers and customer success team

#### 2018 - 2020

# **ADMINISTRATIVE ROLE**

"Atomchip Group" in BGU's Physics department

- Management of the team's purchases and budget
- Management of contact with different role-players in BGU (in charge of purchases, budget, research & administration)
- for team members traveling abroad and their international guests
- General logistical management of team's activity

# **EDUCATION**

#### 2017 - 2020

## **BEN-GURION UNIVERSITY**

Information Systems Management • Final project at University's Internal audit office - with Sharepoint

 Main courses: OOP, BI, WEB, CRM, Databases, IT Infrastructure Algorithms and Complexity

#### 2015

## **WINGATE INSTITUTE**

Basketball Coaches Course